I can't believe it.
（アオバ）信じられないよ。
I know. I never knew that
Lord Tsuchikage could be so crazy.
あぁ。　まさか　土影様ってのが→
ここまで
ふざけた方だとは思わなかった。
（オオノキ）ったく…
また　腰に負担がかかるわい。
Damn it... I'm going to strain
my back again!
Are you sure about this?
（赤ツチ）大丈夫ダニか？
海を行ったほうが…。
Wouldn't it be better to
go by sea?
それに
こんな上空まで上がんなくても…。
Also, we don't have to fly
so high, do we?
（黒ツチ）バカ　言ってんじゃねえぞ
赤ツチ！
Don't be ridiculous, Akatsuchi!
That giant snake might
sense us again!
また　あのでか蛇に
感知されっだろ！
そろそろじゃぜ。
We're almost there.
ASSEMBLE!
ALLIED SHINOBI FORCES!
（ナルト）また　天地が
ひっくり返ったってばよ。
The world flipped over again.
いったい
この島は　どうなってんだ？
What's happening on
this island anyway?
外の様子　見に行ったっきり
ヤマト隊長も帰ってこねえし…。
Captain Yamato went to check
what's going on outside,
but he hasn't come back.
やっぱ
なんか　あったんじゃねえのか？
Don't you think
something happened?
その件については
詳しく調べてもらってる。
We're already looking into that.
You don't have to worry about it.
お前は心配すんな。
ここでの任務は
もう終わったんだ！
My mission here is done!
俺は　さっさと木ノ葉に帰って
サスケを待つ！
I'm going back to
the Hidden Leaf Village
to wait for Sasuke!
アイツと俺には　約束がある。
He and I...made an oath.
（サスケ）まだか？
Not yet?
（ゼツ）まだだ。　じっとしていろ。
Not yet. Just sit still.
次に　ものを見るときは
まるで　別世界になってるよ。
The next time you use your eyes,
you'll see a completely
different world.
This is going to be fun!
おもしろくなりそうだ。
フン…　お前らの戦争なんて
知ったこっちゃないが→
I could care less about your war.
木ノ葉を潰すのは　この俺だ。
The one who will destroy
the Hidden Leaf will be me.
（ランカ）アンコさん
少し　休んでください。
Anko, please rest a little.
You've been working nonstop.
こう　ずっと
張りつめっぱなしじゃ…。
（アンコ）開戦は目前だ。
War is at our doorstep.
だからこそ　少しでも多くの情報を
集めなくちゃならない。
So we have to gather as
much intel as possible.
私たちの情報で
救われる仲間がいるのなら…。
Especially if our intel
can save our comrades.
（ムタ）来た！
They're here!
《ムタ：ウソだろ…》
You're kidding, right?!
（トクマ）さっき
ここへ入っていった白蛇…。
The white snake that
crawled in earlier...
That chakra...is Kabuto's.
あのチャクラ…　カブトだ。
やはり　ここが　アジトだな。
This is the hideout, after all.
蟲に　あたりを探索させた。
I sent my insects to investigate.
地下に
かなりの生体反応を示している。
They've sensed significant
signs of life underground.
トクマ！　下だ。　４時の方向。
Tokuma, down below!
Towards four o'clock!
日向一の白眼なら
捉えられるはずだ。
Your Hyuga Byakugan will be able
to perceive what's down there!
頼む　トクマ。
Please, Tokuma!
白眼！
Byakugan!
こ…　これは！
Th-This is...
何が見えた？　トクマ！
What do you see, Tokuma?!
ランカ！　本部への連絡の準備だ。
Ranka! Prepare to contact
Headquarters!
なんて数だ…。
So many of them...
動物たちは外に出てんのに　なんで
俺は出してもらえねえんだよ！？
How come the animals get
to go outside, but I can't?!
（キラービー）慌てん坊のナルト
あわや損だぜ。
Impatient Naruto...
Haste makes waste...
尾獣のチャクラ　コントロールしきってない。
You still haven't mastered
Tailed Beast Chakra control.
So your training,
I shall personally patrol...
俺様が　お前の修業を仕切る。
修業後は
尾獣チャクラ　お前の手足と同じ感覚。
When we we're done,
Tailed Beast Chakra will feel
like an extension of you...
本物の手足と錯覚。
They'll feel like your arms and legs,
it's true...
ウィー！
Yeaaahh!
おぉ！
尾獣チャクラで　つかまえる！
Whoa...
With your Tailed Beast Chakra...
Catch them!
積み石　積むんす。
Stack 'em up like building blocks...
己と尾獣チャクラでバランス！
Using your chakra and
the Tailed Beast's...
Balance those rocks!
はぁ～。
《モトイ：食いついた！　ナイスだ　ビー》
He took the bait!
Nice work, Bee!
やってみろ。
Try it out.
ウッス！　九尾チャクラでやるんだな。
All right. I have to use
the Nine Tails' chakra, right?
《この岩を崩れねえように
積み上げればいいんだよな》
I have to stack up these rocks
so that they don't tumble, right?
よっしゃ！　やってやるってばよ！
All right! I'll do it!
暴走はない。
一応　コントロールはできてるが→
Don't be reckless there.
Your control is fair.
細やかなコントロール　できてない。
But you don't have
fine-tuned control.
《石を壊してしまった。
掴むのすら　難しいのか…》
He pulverized the rock.
Is it too hard to grasp?
Damn it!
チクショウ！　もう一度だってばよ。
One more time!
《今度は　そ～っと…》
Gently...this time...
《もうちょっと優しく…》
More gently...
Put spirit in...leave power out.
気合を入れろ　力は入れない。
よっしゃ～！
１個で喜んでちゃ→
All right!
Don't get all satisfied with just one...
Or you'll never get done!
一向に進まない。
まだまだ簡単。　次こそ肝心。
The first one is always easy...
The next one is key and
it won't go so breezy.
《うまいぞ　ビー！
これで十分　時間を稼げるはずだ》
Great, Bee! This will buy us
plenty of time.
（我愛羅）いよいよだな。
（エー）両天秤のジジイめ→
The time has come.
It seems that old Fence Sitter
brought them here safely.
無事　連れてきたようだ。
このまま　ビーと九尾は
島ガメごと　本部後方にかくまう。
We'll hide Turtle Island along
with Bee and the Nine Tails
at the rear of our headquarters.
依存はないな？　綱手姫よ。
Any objections, Princess Tsunade?
（綱手）あぁ。
Fine.
（メイ）では　私は土影様の
お迎えにまいりましょう。
I will go and
welcome Lord Tsuchikage.
倒れるなよ…。
Don't fall. Stay put...stay put.
そのまま…。
あっ…　あ～っ！
《惜しい！
今のは　島ガメが揺れたせいだ。
– That was so close!
– Damn it!
– Turtle Island just shook.
– One more time!
ってことは
どうやらもう　着いたか》
Does that mean we've reached
our destination?
（黒ツチ）やっと着いたぜ　ジジイ。
We're finally here, old man!
イテテテ…　腰が…。
また　ムリすっからだよ。
Ouch! My back!
That's because you overdid it!
お疲れさまです　土影様。
Welcome back, Lord Tsuchikage.
それで　状況は？
So what is the situation?
八尾　九尾とも無事だ。
Both the Eight and
Nine Tails are fine.
ただ　九尾の見張り役だった
木遁使いがさらわれた。
But the Wood User that was
guarding the Nine Tails was taken.
さらわれた！？
やられたのではなく？
Taken? Not taken down?
それでは　敵にこちらの
更なる情報が…。
Then the enemy will learn
everything about us!
とにかくじゃ
詳しいことは中で話す。
At any rate,
I'll go over the details inside!
（マダラ）さっさと
ゼツのパワーアップとやらを→
Will you hurry up and start
making Zetsu stronger?
始めてもらおうか。
（カブト）その前に→
Before that, extracting intel
from Yamato takes priority.
このヤマトから
情報を取り出すのが先だ。
ただし　殺さないでもらいたい。
But please don't kill him.
ゼツたちを　更に強くしたいならね。
If you want Zetsu and
the others to get stronger.
輪廻眼人間道の術を使えば
簡単に情報を取り出せるが→
I could use the jutsu of
the Ningendo's Rinnegan...
and easily extract the intel.
コイツが死ぬ。　ゼツを強くするには→
But that would kill him.
So it's better to keep him alive
to make Zetsu stronger?
生かしたままのほうが
いいってことか？
あぁ。
Yes.
《毒か？　これで　木遁の力を
抑えこんでいるな。
Poison, huh?
So that's how he's suppressing
the power of the Wood Style.
カブトめ…　よく　初代　柱間の細胞を
研究している》
Damn that Kabuto.
He has researched the cells of
the First Hashirama quite thoroughly.
僕が作った
柱間の力を抑制する薬さ。
It's a drug I made to
curtail Hashirama's power.
大丈夫　ゼツたちには使わない。
Don't worry,
I won't use it on the Zetsu.
《たしかに…　培養したゼツたちは
柱間の細胞によるものだ。
Without a doubt,
he cultivated all those Zetsu
from Hashirama's cells.
コイツに使っている毒を
使われたら…。
If he were to use this poison
on them...
フッ…　ずいぶんと
こっちの手の内を→
That Orochimaru...
He really looked deep
into our organization.
調べてやがったな　大蛇丸め》
《ヤマト：くっ…　体が動かない。
I can't move. Damn it!
クソ！　これじゃあ　己の覚悟を
実行することすらできない！
I can't even execute
my own decisions like this!
うっ…　このままだと…。
At this rate... Damn it!
チクショウ！　みんな　すまない…》
Forgive me, everyone!
輪廻眼の力を使わなくても→
We don't need the power
of the Rinnegan.
僕の自白剤とキミの写輪眼の
二つ押しで十分　情報は取れる。
With my truth serum...
and your Sharingan, we can
glean all the intel we want.
相手がわかれば
ソイツらの最も不得意で→
If we learn who the enemy is,
we can strike them by sending out
their worst enemy.
苦手な相手を選抜して
ぶつけられる。
チャクラの無駄遣いを
する必要もなくなるってわけさ。
There's no need to waste chakra.
SEALED
おっ…。
Huh?!
That's the Hidden Leaf's!
あれは木ノ葉の…。
新しい情報だ。
It must be new intel!
回収しろ！
Retrieve it!
（シカク）×印が　敵のアジトと確定。
The X marks the enemy's hideout.
山岳の墓場と呼ばれるところだ。
It's known as
the Mountain Graveyard.
陸路を通れば
湯隠れと霜隠れを通ってくる。
If we go by land,
we'll pass through
the Hidden Steam Village and
the Hidden Frost Village.
（我愛羅）湯　霜隠れを有する
二国に避難勧告を。
Advise both nations that possess the Steam
and the Frost villages to evacuate!
（シカク）潜入偵察隊からの
情報によると→
According to reports by
the Infiltration and Recon Unit,
敵の数　約１０万。
その大連隊移動を考えると→
the enemy is roughly
100,000 strong.
When one considers mobilizing
a regiment of that size,
海上ルートから来るのは
少数と考えられるが→
I think only a fraction of them
will come by sea.
取り囲まれると　やばい。
We'll be in a bind
if they surround us.
（ミフネ）こうなれば　どっちが
先手を打つかで勝敗が決まる。
Then it'll all comes down to
who makes the first move!
まず　奇襲部隊に招集をかけろ。
Convene the Ambush Unit immediately!
Have the main regiment run
through their formations!
それから　集めた戦闘大連隊も
隊を組ませて→
それぞれ陣形を確認させろ。
（サムイ）はっ。
Yes sir!
同じく　後方支援医療部隊には→
Make sure the Medical Unit
is well supplied
医療忍具を携帯させておけ。
with medical ninja tools!
シカク　お前は情報部隊の
情報ルートチェックも合わせてやれ。
Shikaku, help the Intel Unit check
their chain of communication.
（シカク）了解。
Roger.
感知部隊の青に連絡。
そっちも急いで。
Contact Ao and the Sensory Unit.
Have them hurry!
Y-Yes.
（長十郎）は…　はい。
（我愛羅）土影。
Tsuchikage, these were finished
while you were away.
アンタたちが出かけている間に
これができた。
Oh! So they're done!
おお　もうできたのか。
受け取れ。
Take it.
SHINOBI
Headbands for
the Allied Shinobi Forces, eh?
（オオノキ）ああ…
それが忍連合の額当てか。
なかなかじゃぜ。
Nice work!
I came up with the design.
某が　デザインした。
かつて争いあった　あなた方も
いまや　ひとつの忍である。
Former enemies who once
battled each other
are now one shinobi force!
更に　今　忍と侍とが手を組む。
さあ　いよいよでござる。
Furthermore, shinobi and samurai
have joined together.
The time is near!
次！
– Next!
– Yes!
はい！
（カンクロウ）俺が　奇襲部隊隊長を
任された砂のカンクロウだ。
I am Kankuro of the Sand,
appointed captain of
the Ambush Unit.
（サイ）カンクロウさん…　ですね。
あだ名は何にしましょう？
Kankuro, you say?
What should be your nickname?
な…　なぁ？
Huh?!
Is that wise?
《オモイ：大丈夫なのか？
こんな若いヤツが隊長で…。
Naming someone so young
the captain...
もし…　もしも
若気の至りで作戦を失敗して→
What if...what if...
Because of his inexperience,
he messes up and panics
不安にさいなまれた挙句→
and forces me to become
the acting captain…
俺に臨時の隊長の役を
押しつけてきたら…。
ああ　どうしよう…》
Oh man, what'll I do?!
額当ての配布　終了。
The headbands have been distributed!
医療物資　チェック終了。
Medical supplies have been checked!
Provisions have been checked!
食糧確認。
誰だ　家畜担当。
豚が逃げ出しているぞ。
Who is in charge of the livestock?!
A pig's escaped!
The Captain is here!
Everyone, fall in!
隊長が来たぞ。　全員整列！
（シズネ）私が　この部隊の
指揮をとるよう　おおせつかった→
My name is Shizune and
I have been named to lead this unit.
シズネといいます。
皆さん　よろしくです。
Good to meet you all.
First, there is something I want
all of you to remember.
最初に皆さんに覚えておいて
もらいたいことがあります。
この子は　食糧ではありません。
This one is not food!
（天画）いのいちさんですね。
You're Inoichi, right?
（いのいち）キミは？
私は　天画。
And you are?
I'm Tenga! I've heard
so much about you!
あなたの噂は聞いてます。
ぜひ　今度映像として記録を。
Please let me put you
on videotape and...
遅れてすみません。
I'm sorry I'm late.
聞いている。
大変だったようだな　アオバ。
I heard...
What a rough time you had, Aoba.
はい。　ヤマトが…。
Yes, Yamato was...
だが　今は忘れろ。
But put that out of your mind now.
各部隊との連絡を
俺たち情報部隊が仕切る。
We, the Intel Unit, will oversee
all communication
between units.
情報は正確かつ
迅速に伝達しなければならない。
Intel must be transmitted
accurately and quickly!
そのためには　俺たちが
どんな情報を聞こうとも→
In order to do that,
we must maintain calm at all times,
no matter what we hear!
冷静でなければならないのだ。
Understand?!
いいか？
（みんな）はい！
– Yes!
（シー）ハァー　戦争か。
（青）シー君だったか。
A war, huh?
Your name was Cee, right?
Is this your first war?!
キミは　戦争は初めてか？
はい。
Yes...
俺たちは忍連合のいわば目だ。
We are the "eyes" of
the Allied Shinobi Force.
この部隊の出来次第で
戦況は大きく流れが変わる。
Our unit's performance can greatly
change the tide of battle.
その目を曇らせるなよ。
Stay focused and alert.
わかりました　青隊長。
I understand, Captain Ao!
うん。
皆も気を抜くなよ。
（みんな）はっ！
Everyone, don't let down
your guard!
– Yes sir!
（チョウジ）５つの部隊に
わけるって聞いたから→
I heard they were going to
split us up into five units.
てっきり　里ごとに
わかれると思ってたのに。
So I figured they'd group us
by village.
（シカマル）んなわけねえだろ。
戦争なんだぜ。
That's not going to happen.
This is a war.
（テマリ）そういうことだ。
He's right.
里同士で手柄を
取り合ってる場合ではない。
This is no time to be competing
with other villages!
だな。
Yeah...
戦闘大連隊は　それこそ
戦闘に特化した５つの部隊だ。
The main regiment is
made up of five units,
each specializing in warfare.
第１部隊は中距離での戦闘を
得意とする忍で構成されている。
The First Company:
Mid-Range Battle Unit
comprised of shinobi who excel
in mid-distance combat.
暗器や武器を使う忍がメインだ。
Made up mostly of shinobi
who are weapons users.
第２部隊は
近接戦闘に特化した部隊。
The Second Company:
Close-Range Battle Unit
specializes in close combat.
戦闘大連隊のなかでも
最前線で戦う忍たちだ。
The shinobi of this unit will be fighting
on the front lines.
第３部隊は　中距離と
近距離の間をサポートする部隊。
The Third Company:
Intermediate-Range Battle Unit
will be stationed to provide support
up close and at mid-range.
ここは
スピードと体力がないと務まらない。
To be part of this unit, one must have
speed and physical strength.
俺たちは遠距離部隊だな。
This is the Fourth Company:
Long-Range Battle Unit.
情報部隊との連携を密にして
前線のサポート。
We will provide the link with
the Intel Unit to support the front lines.
それに　後方支援部隊の
盾になる必要もある。
In addition,
we must act as the shield
for the support units
behind the lines.
そして　特殊な忍術や
攻撃方法を持つ戦闘特別部隊。
And finally, the Fifth Company:
Special-Range Battle Unit
with their specialized ninjutsu
and attack tactics!
特別部隊？
A Special Unit?
Yes... In war, anything can happen.
ああ。　戦争じゃ何が起きても
不思議じゃねえ。
部隊分けをしたものの
実際　きれいに部隊ごとに→
Even if we're broken up
into units,
it's wishful thinking to believe that
わかれて戦うなんてことは
稀だろう。
each team will operate
without a hitch.
そして戦況によっては
有利な戦場　不利な戦場ができる。
Depending on the situation, some units will
find themselves in good battlefield position,
while others will be at
a disadvantage.
それをカバーできるのは主に
秘伝忍術を持ってる忍たちだ。
This is where we'll rely
on the shinobi
who possess secret ninjutsu.
Can't say that all preparations
have been made,
準備万端とは言いがたいが→
総勢　約８万の忍を　短期間で
ここまで部隊編成できたのは→
but considering roughly
80,000 shinobi have been organized
into units this quickly...
木ノ葉の頭脳
奈良シカクのおかげだな。
You've got to hand it to the brains
behind the Hidden Leaf, Shikaku Nara.
お前　親父に恥をかかすなよ。
You'd better not embarrass your dad.
So the war is about to begin.
戦争が…　始まるんだね。
隊長たちだ！
Captains!
（みんな）おお！
（シカマル）第１部隊隊長。
The captain of the First Company,
known as the Raikage's
right-hand man,
雷影の右腕とも言われる
雲隠れ　ダルイ。
Darui of the Hidden Cloud.
第２部隊隊長　岩隠れの黄ツチ。
第３部隊隊長は　カカシさんだ。
第５部隊隊長は
鉄の国の大将　ミフネ。
そして　うちらの第４部隊長兼→
すべての戦闘部隊を指揮するのが
風影　我愛羅。
♪～
時は来た。
口寄せ　穢土転生！
♪～
まずは　元暁のメンバー。
イタチ　サソリ　デイダラ　角都　そして長門。
更に元人柱力のメンバー。
二尾ユギト　三尾やぐら
四尾の老紫　五尾ハン→
六尾ウタカタ　七尾フウ。
続いて元五影前任者たち。
二代目土影　三代目雷影
四代目風影。
そして爆遁のガリ
鬼人　再不斬　氷遁の白。
山椒魚のハンゾウ
砂のチヨバア　かぐや一族の君麻呂。
木ノ葉より　猿飛アスマ　ダン　日向ヒザシ。
その他もろもろ
名のあった手だれたち。
それだけじゃない。
柱間の生きた細胞を持つ
ヤマトを使ったんだ。
やはり　うまく馴染んだようだね。
（カブト）歴代の名だたる忍たちに
強化された１０万の白ゼツ。
フフフ…　壮観だね。
行くぞ。
第四次忍界大戦。
開戦だ。
（リー）ノォー！
タイツが縮んでしまいました！
今日　着ていこうと思った服が
ありません！
あっ　そういえば
古より伝わりし呼吸法で→
筋肉の伸縮を自在に操り…。
ヒュッヒュッ　ファッファッ　ヒュッヒュツ！
よし！
ファイト！　ファイト！　フィイト！
（リー）ギャー！！